Abhishek Malik

Web Developer

VIT University, Vellore 9003695866 maps.abhishek@gmail.com

I am a third year student at VIT-Vellore pursuing Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and Engineering. I am a tech enthusiast and Web developer for past two years. I love creating applications and contributing towards society by volunteering as well as organizing different events.

SKILLS

HTML5 & CSS3, Bootstrap, Python, Python-Flask, C++, C, Data Structures, MySQL, Javascript, jQuery, JSON, NLTK, Pygal, Matplotlib, scikit-learn, Python/Django/Flask, Website Development/Design, Web Application Development, REST APIs, Experience in Linux - Kali Linux and Ubuntu.

EXPERIENCE

Enactus VIT Vellore - Founding member and Project Lead

October 2017 - Present

- Worked towards social entrepreneurship, making sustainable solutions using the gained skills.
- Launched Project Envision to help visually challenged,

Helto Services - Web Development intern

April 2017 - June 2017

 Developed the website and JSON REST API to support the android application. Also understood different specification required by the client and added them to the project.

IEEE VIT - Technical core

Sept 2015 - Jan 2017

 Volunteered for and organized several technical and non-technical events such as make-a-thon, spax and enigma.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech), Information Systems (2015 - 2019)

VIT University

CGPA: 8.56/10

XII (Senior Secondary), Science

Year of Completion: 2015

CBSE Board (DAV Public School, Sreshtha Vihar, Delhi)

Percentage: 94.20%

X (Secondary)

Year of Completion: 2013

CBSE Board (Maharaja Agarsain Public School)

CGPA: 10.00/10

PROJECTS

Project Envision

Sep 2017 - Present

http://projectenvision.in

This project creates job opportunities or visually challenged through business process outsourcing call center. In this project we provide visually challenged with an easy to use application.

Trace your college path

Mar 2016 - Apr 2016

https://drive.google.com/open?id=1niRR9MavINZHMz7W-rGQg0n9UzVNm0Xh

Map using data structures which has the unique ability to point to a maximum of four next nodes or checkpoints. Each data structure so made can further point to another four checkpoints and so on. User can create a whole map and trace the path.

Call data Analysis application

Sep 2017 - Oct 2017

This project became an helping hand for analyzing the data in project envision. Call data and responses of calls made by employees are taken and displayed through beautiful python library - pygal.

Flyshop(Implemented and wrote a review paper)

Mar 2017 - May 2017

Implemented and wrote a review paper which got accepted in

IJCSE JOURNAL.

Provide a Direct Link between Consumer and Retailer and compared the prices with different websites using BeautifulSoup library in python.

Turing Machine Simulator

Sep 2016 - Oct 2016

New data structures were devised to simulate the pointer, the infinite tape and for storage of states.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Project Lead and Founding member at Enactus-VIT Vellore.
- Member at Toastmasters-VIT FOGO Club.(Received Best Speaker, Best Evaluator and Best Table-Topic speaker in the sessions).
- Core committee member at IEEE-VIT(2015-2017).
- Youngest Prefect for a School House in class 10th.